God, that is the most beautiful
engagement ring ever!
이렇게 아름다운
약혼반지는 처음 본다
수백 개를 사들인
네 말이니 믿어줄게
You should know.
You bought, like, a billion of them.
넌 하나도 못 받았지
You didn't get one.
드디어 오늘밤이야
-Tonight's the big night.
-How you gonna ask her?
청혼은 어떻게 할래?
준비는 완벽해
근사한 레스토랑에 데려가서
We're gonna go to her
favorite restaurant.
I'm gonna get her favorite champagne.
She'll know how expensive it is.
모니카가 가격을 잘 알고 있는
값비싼 샴페인을 시키는 거야
When the glasses are full, instead of
proposing a toast, I'm gonna propose.
그리고 잔이 가득 차면
건배를 제안하는 대신
청혼하겠어
It sounds perfect!
- 완벽하다
- 그렇지?
넌 위태로워, 내가 할게
-You'll mess it up. Let me do it.
-I won't mess it up.
잘할 수 있어
만약 거절당하면
이 반지 나 가져도 돼?
-lf she says no, can I have the ring?
-She won't say no.
- 거절을 왜 당해
- 만약에
If.
그래라
-Sure.
-What about me? I want it too.
그럼 난?
나도 갖고 싶어
-She won't say no.
-I'll let you borrow it.
거절할 리 없어
필요하면 빌려줄게
- 얘들아
- 어서 와
안녕, 모니카
Hey, Monica.
이리 줘
-Give it.
-It's gone.
넘어갔어
Phoebe.
피비
안녕, 모니카
Hey, Monica!
We're practically kissing.
키스나 다름없네
The One With the Proposal
- 나 왔어
- 안녕, 레이첼
Anyone free tonight? My boss is
hosting a charity event for kids.
누구 오늘밤에 시간 있어?
부장님이 불우아동 돕기
자선파티를 여는데
The more people I bring,
the better I look. Monica? Chandler?
많이 데려가서 점수 좀 따야지
모니카랑 챈들러는 어때?
We can't go.
We're going to dinner. Remember?
모니카랑 챈들러는
저녁약속 있다, 잊었어?
내 정신 좀 봐, 미안해
-Oh, my God. I'm so sorry.
-What's the big deal?
왜 정색을 하고 그래?
레이첼이 우리 계획을
까먹으면 화난단 말이야
I get mad when Rachel doesn't
remember where we're going.
Where are you going?
무슨 계획인데?
-How about you guys?
-Open bar?
- 너희들은 어때?
- 술은 공짜니?
-I think so.
-I can do that for the kids.
그럴 거야
좋은 일인데 가야지
나도 갈게
I'll come. I'm making money.
It's time I give some back.
이젠 나도 돈을 버니까
일부는 사회에 환원해야지
내 돈부터 갚는 게
순서 아닐까?
You could give back
the money you owe me.
Okay. Have a benefit.
차라리 연금을 부어라
- 안녕
- 로스
Ross, can you go
to a charity event tonight?
너 오늘 저녁
자선행사에 올 수 있니?
I have plans with Elizabeth.
안 돼, 엘리자베스랑 약속 있어
넌 벌써 애들을 돕고 있구나
You're already doing
your part for the kids.
미안하다, 엘리자베스가
내일 수련회 떠나게 됐거든
It's our last night before she
leaves for camp. To be a counselor.
지도교사의 임무를 띠고
I have a question. All jokes aside,
where is this relationship going?
오빠, 하나만 묻자
농담은 다 접어두고
정말 어떻게 할 작정이야?
농담을 접어두다니
난 동의한 적 없어
All jokes aside?
I didn't agree to that.
- 오래갈 관계라고 생각해?
- 글쎄
-Do you see this as long-term?
-I don't know.
넌 걔보다 12살 위야
-You are 12 years older than her.
-Who's counting?
그걸 누가 신경 써?
엘리자베스가 신경 쓰지
이 정도 차이니까
Well, she is. She's this many.
로스, 너무 어리잖아
Ross, she is really young.
다들 그렇게 생각하니?
Does everyone feel this way?
-Yeah, sort of.
-Sorry.
- 그렇다고 볼 수 있지
- 미안하다
난 너희들이 그냥 재미로
그러는 줄로만 알았는데
I thought you were just making jokes.
I had no idea.
You guys are wrong. Yes, there is
a chronological age difference.
하지만 너희 생각이 틀렸어
물리적인 나이차는 있지만
난 그런 거 잘 못 느껴
굉장히 성숙한 애라서
But I never notice it,
because she is very mature.
It doesn't matter what you guys think.
I'm dating Elizabeth, not you.
그리고 너희들 생각은
별로 중요하지 않아
엘리자베스와 사귀는 건
나지 너희가 아니니까
걘 간밤에 그렇게
얘기 안 하던데?
Not what she said last night.
See, now, he could date her.
조이 정도라면 어울리지
Will you marry me?
결혼해줄래?
결혼해주겠어?
너 나랑 결혼해
Hey, you marry me.
무슨 일이야, 꼬마요정들?
-What's going on, little elves?
-It's the big night. We wish you luck.
중요한 밤이잖아
행운을 빌어주려고
-You have the ring?
-In my pocket.
반지는 잘 챙겼지?
그럼, 이 주머니에
-Phoebe.
-Wha..?
피비
이제 그만 나가 줘
모니카가 눈치 채면 곤란해
Will you guys get out of here?
This is a surprise.
그래, 너희들 어서 나가
Yeah, you guys. Get out of here.
Hey, guys.
안녕, 얘들아
정말 예쁘다
-You look beautiful.
-Thank you.
고마워
왜들 이래?
What's going on?
We're just really...
그냥 오늘...
excited about this charity event
we have to go to.
자선행사에 갈
생각을 하니 목이 멘다
- 여기
- 고마워
-Here.
-Thank you.
근데 이게 다 뭐래니?
-So, what's going on here?
-Well, this is a silent auction.
이건 서면경매라는 건데
They lay the stuff here.
You write down your offer.
여기 진열된 물품을 보고
사람들이 입찰가를 적으면
Then the highest bid gets it.
최고가에 낙찰되는 거지
나도 서면경매가
뭔지는 아는데
I know what a silent auction is.
What's going on with your hair?
네 머리가 어떻게 된 거냐고
- 이게 왜?
- 아냐, 정말 예뻐
-Why?
-No, it's nice.
Nice to see you.
So glad you brought someone.
- 왔군요, 레이첼
- 안녕하세요
손님을 모셔왔네요
손님 정도가 아니라
1개 부대예요
Someone? I brought people.
부장님, 친구 피비예요
우리 부서 톰슨 부장님이셔
Phoebe, this is Mr. Thompson.
He's the head of my department.
반갑습니다
-And I also brought my friend Joey.
-Shrimp toast!
조이라는 친구도 왔는데...
오! 새우 토스트다!
어디 갔는지 안 보이네요
You know, I don't know where he is.
입찰 좀 했나요?
I hope you'll bid.
Actually, I was about to bid
on this lovely trip to Paris.
안 그래도 이 파리여행권이
어떨까 생각 중이에요
- 탁월한 선택이군요
- 네
-Nice choice. Good luck.
-Thank you.
- 행운을 빌어요
- 감사합니다
Okay.
좋아, 20달러
Twenty dollars.
빨랑 문 닫아
Shut the door! Shut the door!
뭐하는 거야?
-What's going on?
-Guys are throwing water balloons.
건너편 남자애들이
물풍선을 던지잖아요
Call the cops. That's what I did
to kids in my building.
경찰에 신고해, 우리 건물
꼬맹이들도 가끔 저러거든
아뇨, 물풍선 전쟁놀이예요
우리가 시작했어요
No, it's a water balloon fight.
We started it.
저기..
I stopped by to see if you wanted
to see this play tonight.
오늘밤 연극 한 편
보는 게 어떨까 하고
It's excellent. The director is..
괜찮은 작품이야, 연출자가...
가미카제 누가 다 마셨어?
-Who drank all the kamikazes?
-Nobody. We put them in here!
마신 게 아니라 여기 들었지
- 드실래요?
- 됐어, 그만
You want some?
좋아, 잠깐 나랑
얘기 좀 할까?
-Could I talk to you for a second?
-Yeah, sure.
그래요
So this play, what do you think?
이 연극 어때?
평도 상당히 좋고...
-It's gotten great reviews..
-Attack!
공격!
- 물풍선 내려놔!
- 너희나 내려놔!
-Put your balloons down!
-You put your balloons down!
빨리 내려놔!
Everybody put their balloons down!
양쪽 다 물풍선
바닥에 내려놔!
이거 무지 비싼 옷이야
Now, this is a nice suit!
괜찮다면 잠시 엘리자베스와
단둘이 얘기하고 싶군
If you'll excuse us...
I would like to speak
to Elizabeth alone for a moment.
야, 엘리자베스
너희 아빠 밥맛이다
Whoa, Liz. Your dad's a bummer.
다음은 낭만적인
파리여행권입니다
Our next item is
the romantic trip to Paris.
낙찰자는 에밀 알렉산더
2,300달러를 제시하셨군요
It goes to Emil Alexander
with a high bid of $2300.
아! 조금만 더 쓸 걸
So close!
얘들아, 이거 봐
마실 거 가져왔어
Guys, look. Got me some drinks.
무슨 짓이야?
-What are you doing?
-Open bar.
공짜 바잖아
이젠 텅 빈 바겠다
Well, now it's an empty bar.
넌 남 즐기는 꼴을
못 보는구나
You can't stand anyone else
enjoying themselves, can you?
마지막으로 오늘의 하이라이트
Finally, our biggest item.
전장 22피트
가족 레저용 요트
The 22-foot
Gentleman's Daysailer sailboat.
The winning bid
was a whopping $20,000.
낙찰가는 자그마치 2만 달러
I won.
내가 맞혔어
정확히 찍었다고
That was my guess.
뭐? 뭐야? 뭐라고?
-What? What? What?
-I guessed $20,000.
내가 2만 달러 찍었어
조이, 이건 경매야
찍는 게 아니라 사는 거라고
Joey, it is an auction.
You don't guess. You buy!
뭐?
What?
I don't have $20,000.
나한테 2만 달러가 어디 있어
요트의 새 주인입니다
조이 트리비아니
Congratulations on your new boat,
Joey Tribbiani.
조이, 앉아
Joey, sit down.
괜찮아, 이 순간을 즐겨
Forget her. You enjoy this.
뭐하는 거야?
What are you doing?
자랑스러운 성조기 앞에
"One nation...
under God, indivisible,
with liberty and justice for all."
몸과 마음을 바쳐
충성을 다할 것을
굳게 다짐합니다
아직 안 까먹었네
샴페인 왔구나
I remembered it.
The champagne is here.
-You okay?
-Yes. I'm good. Are you good?
괜찮아?
그럼, 괜찮지, 괜찮고말고
넌 어때? 좋아? 좋고말고야?
Is everything..? Are you perfect?
그럼, 다 좋은데
조금 추워
Yeah. I'm okay.
Actually, I'm a bit cold.
Can I have your jacket?
- 재킷 좀 벗어줄래?
- 그럼
어허, 안 될 말이지
No, you can't have my jacket.
그럼 내가 춥잖아
Because then I would be cold.
If you thought you'd be cold,
you should've brought a jacket.
날이 쌀쌀하면
자기 옷을 가져와야지
그거 빼고 다른 건 괜찮아?
But, other than that, are you okay?
자기야말로 괜찮은 거야?
-Are you sure you're okay?
-Yes. I'm fine.
그래, 난 좋아
In fact, I've been fine
for a long time now and I think...
사실 요즘 이렇게
잘 지낼 수 있는 건...
다 자기 덕분이야
the reason is you.
고마워
That's sweet.
그래
자기를 만나기 전에
난 정말 한심하게 살았어
Before I met you,
I had really little life.
그래서 앞으로 남은 인생을...
-And I couldn't imagine growing old..
-Oh, my God.
- 맙소사
- 알아, 끝까지 들어봐
-I know. But let me say it.
-Richard.
맙소사, 리처드
뭐? 난 챈들러야
What? I'm Chandler.
Oh, that's Richard.
오, 저건 리처드네
Maybe he won't see us. Richard!
우릴 못 봤겠지? 리처드!
모니카, 챈들러
Monica. Chandler.
내가 왜 이러지?
I don't know why I did that.
-Good to see you.
-You too. You let your hair grow.
오랜만이네요
그래, 머리가 많이 길었군
네, 긴 머리 좋아했으면서
That's right. You always wanted me to.
콧수염 다시 기르시네요?
-I see your mustache is back.
-Well, my nose got lonely.
코가 시려서
You don't have a mustache,
which is good.
그쪽은 콧수염이 없군요
다행입니다
챈들러라고 합니다, 불편한
자리에선 농담을 남발하죠
Chandler. I make jokes
when I'm uncomfortable.
- 반가워요, 리사예요
- 안녕하세요
-Hi, I'm Lisa.
-Hi.
이런, 내 정신 좀 보게
I'm sorry. Lisa, Monica, Chandler.
We used to date.
모니카와 챈들러야
전에 사귄 적이 있지
Richard, no one's supposed
to know about us.
리처드, 우리 일은
비밀에 부치기로 했잖아요
See? I did it again.
보세요, 또 나왔죠?
-Chandler, sit down.
-I'll sit down.
- 챈들러, 우리 그만 앉자
- 그래, 앉자고
반가웠어요
-Good to see you.
-Your table's ready, sir.
자리 준비됐습니다
- 반가웠네
- 네
Good to see you guys.
If you prefer, this table's available.
이 자리도 비었습니다만
그거 재미있겠네
That might be fun.
-What were you thinking?
-I didn't know it was an auction.
정신이 있는 거니?
- 경매인 줄 몰랐다니까
- 뭐?
찍기 놀이인 줄 알았지
I figured I'd take a guess.
Help a charity. Free boat!
자선단체 도와주고
공짜 요트 생기고
자선단체가 왜
공짜로 요트를 줘?
Why would a charity give away a boat?
I don't know. Charity?
난들 알아?
자선하려고?
망할 보트 그냥 사버려
Well, just buy the damn boat.
피비
Don't you think
you've had enough to drink?
- 너무 많이 마시는 거 아냐?
- 청소년을 돕고 있잖아
I'm just helping the kids.
How is you drinking helping the kids?
술 마시는 게 어떻게
청소년을 돕는 거야?
Because the more I drink, the less
there is for the kids to drink.
내가 많이 마실수록
애들 마실 술이 줄어드니까
Mr. Tribbiani,
your contribution brings us...
- 트리비아니 씨
- 네
선생님 덕분에 청소년센터
건립이 성큼 앞당겨졌습니다
a step closer
to building the youth center.
이 분을 모셔와서
얼마나 고마운지 몰라요
-I'm so happy you brought him.
-So am I.
저도 그렇답니다
I'm curious.
How much is that boat worth?
근데 실제 보트 가격이
얼마나 되죠?
아마 1만 9천 달러일 겁니다
-I think it was valued at 19,000.
-Hey, I was pretty close.
봐, 거의 맞혔지?
안타까운 일이지만
So, bad news.
전 그 보트 못 삽니다
돈이 없거든요
I can't buy the boat.
I don't have any money.
조이, 너 정말 웃겼어
Joey! Joey, good one. He's silly.
네, 대단한 유머예요
Good! Very good!
잘한다
-So I think I'm gonna take off now.
-You can't leave, Joey!
그럼 난 이만 가볼게
야, 가긴 어딜 가
You agreed to buy that boat.
It's a contract.
넌 보트 구입에 동의했어
이건 계약이라고
Plus, if you leave,
my boss will kill me.
이렇게 가버리면
난 부장님한테 죽어
그럼 어떡하냐
난 그런 돈 없어
I don't have that kind of money.
나도 알아, 어디 보자...
I know. Okay, okay.
This is what we'll do.
좋아, 이렇게 하자
2위 입찰자한테 가서
We'll let the next
highest bidder buy it.
그 보트를 넘기는 거야
차액은 네가 지불하고
Then you'll pay the difference.
- 좋아
- 그래
Okay. I don't know why the kids
need a youth center anyway.
그나저나 청소년센터 따위가
왜 필요해?
나처럼 방과 후에
TV나 보면 되지
They should just watch TV after school
like I did. I turned out fine.
훌륭하게 잘 컸잖아
훌륭하진 않다
Not great.
애들을 너무 많이 도와서
토할 것 같다
I'm helping the kids so much
I think I'm gonna throw up.
So we're hiding in the bathroom...
그래서 우린 욕실로 숨었죠
부모님이 들어오시는 바람에
모니카는 안에 갇히고 말았지
I get out. But before she can,
her parents come in.
샤워 커튼 뒤로 숨었는데
I hide in the shower.
They start going at it on the floor.
두 분이 욕실 바닥에서
일을 치를 분위기더라구요
세상에...
Oh, my God!
I got a good one.
저도 하나 생각났어요
I once walked in on both my parents
making love to the same guy.
언젠가 부모님이 한 남자랑
하고 있는데 제가 들어갔죠
It's so great seeing you guys again.
I'd like to make a toast.
두 사람을 다시 보니
정말 반갑군
우리 건배할까?
한 시인이 말한 대로
'우정의 감미로움 속에서'
As a poet once said,
"In the sweetness of friendship...
'웃음과 기쁨을 나누고'
Let there be laughter
and sharing of pleasures.
'맑은 이슬 속에서
가슴은 활기찬 아침을 맞네'
In the dew of little things, the heart
finds its morning and is refreshed."
뭐라구요?
What?
세상에, 얘들아
Oh, my God! You guys!
그 전에 너한테
들려줄 얘기가 있어
Have we got a story for you.
Guess who we bumped into?
- 오늘 식당에서 누굴 만났게?
- 누구?
-Who?
-Richard!
리처드
맞아, 리처드도 자주
들르는 곳이지
Right, that's Richard's
favorite place too.
- 알고 있었어?
- 응
-Oh, you knew that? Good.
-Weren't you going out with Elizabeth?
잘했다
엘리자베스 안 만났어?
만나려고 했는데 물풍선
싸움하느라 바쁘더라고
I was. She was a little busy
with a water balloon fight.
어른들한텐 빠져나오지
못할 일이 가끔 생기거든
Sometimes grownups have commitments
they can't get out of.
아무래도 너무 어린가 봐
Maybe she is too young for me.
거기서 친구들이랑 뛰노는 걸
보니까 유모가 된 기분이더라
When I was over there,
I felt like I was a babysitter.
이제 너희들 얘기가
무슨 뜻인지 알겠다
I see what you were talking about.
I don't know what to do.
어떡하냐?
나쁜 점과 좋은 점을
저울질해보는 건 어때?
Weigh the good stuff
about her against the bad.
나도 처음엔 그랬어...
That's what I did when I
first started... weighing stuff.
저울질할 때
좋아, 나쁜 점부터
Okay, bad stuff.
I'm 12 years older than she is.
난 걔보다 12살이 많아
The school could fire you.
학교에서 알면 오빤 해고야
- 엘리자베스는 석 달 정학
- 수련회에 가겠지
-She's leaving for three months.
-For camp.
이번엔 좋은 점
Okay, good stuff.
엘리자베스는
상냥하고 예쁘고...
Well, she's sweet and pretty and..
섹스도 물론 좋겠지?
And the sex is probably great, huh?
It's tender and respectful,
if that's what you mean.
부드럽고 서로를
존중하는 분위기야
The only thing you need to ask is,
"Do you see a future?"
지금 가장 중요한 문제는
장래가 보이냐는 거야
결혼할 수 있을 것 같아?
Do you see yourself marrying her?
My God. You married her, didn't you?
맙소사, 벌써 결혼했구나
아냐, 무슨 소리야
No, I didn't do that. It's just...
솔직히 안 될 것 같아
미래의 모습이 잘 안 그려져
Okay, honestly, no.
I don't see a big future with her.
Okay, I think that's your answer.
그럼 답이 나왔네
I gotta talk to her. I hate this part.
말해야겠다
이런 거 정말 싫은데
Forget Elizabeth.
If you're not careful...
엘리자베스는 잊어버려
너 여차하면 올해는
결혼 못하게 되는 수가 있어
you may not get married
at all this year.
-Weren't you supposed to do something?
-Good luck with Elizabeth, my man.
너 오늘 무슨 일 있다고 했냐?
엘리자베스랑 잘해봐라
맙소사, 너 몇 잔이나 먹었니?
My God, Phoebe, how many have you had?
1, 2, 3... Seven times three..
21!
하나, 둘, 셋, 넷, 다섯, 여섯
7 곱하기 3은 21잔
너 많이 취했어
-You must be just wasted!
-I'm a little tired.
좀 피곤한 것 뿐이야
레이첼
-Next highest bidder is at table one.
-Great.
2위 입찰자가
1번 테이블에 있어
잘됐다
The guy with the Paris trip
is at table four.
그리고 파리여행권 낙찰 받은
사람은 4번 테이블이야
- 알았어
- 파리여행권엔 왜 신경을 써?
-Why do you care about who won?
-It's a trip for two.
2인용 여행권이야
갔다올게
Excuse me.
실례지만 여기 파리여행권
낙찰 받은 분 계신가요?
Is the person who won
the Paris trip at this table?
접니다만
-That was me.
-Enchante.
앙샹테
-Is there a Mr. Bowmont at this table?
-That's me.
실례합니다, 이 테이블에
보먼트 씨라고 계십니까?
저올시다
Well, hello. This is your
lucky day, Mr. Bowmont.
저기, 안녕하세요
운이 좋으신 날이네요
The Gentleman Daysailer
has become available again...
가족 레저용 요트를
사실 수 있게 됐답니다
and I believe you made
a bid of $18,000.
1만 8천 달러를
써내신 걸로 아는데요
You have to pay that.
It's not just a guess.
찍는 게 아니라
돈 내고 사는 거래요
가만있어
I was relieved I didn't win.
My wife would've killed me.
오히려 잘됐다고
생각하는 중이라오
집사람한테 혼날 뻔했어요
You kidding? She'll love this boat!
무슨 말씀, 좋아하실 겁니다
네, 사모님 성함이
어떻게 되시죠?
-What is your wife's name?
-Pam.
팸이오
팸, 세상에나
상상해보세요
Just imagine this: The Pam.
팸...
I don't think she'd like that.
안 좋아할 것 같은데요?
그럼 이건 어때요?
미스터 보먼트...
Okay. Imagine this:
The Mr. Bowmont.
그것도 별로군요
-I don't think so.
-Let me paint you a little picture.
제가 그림을 그려드리죠
좋아요, 허드슨 강에서
돛을 올리면
You are setting sail up the Hudson.
You've got the wind in your... arms.
바람이 머... 팔에 부딪히죠
늘 꿈꿔왔던 평화와
고요를 만끽하면서
You get all that peace and quiet
you've always wanted.
You get back to nature.
You can go fishing.
자연으로 돌아가
낚시를 하는 거예요
You get one of those hats.
People call you captain.
모자 하나만 쓰시면
선장님이 되잖아요
연세가 더 드시면
선장 영감님
And then when you're old, Cappy.
까짓 거 뭐 그렇게 합시다
-It's for a good cause. All right.
-No way! It's mine!
- 잘 생각하셨어요
- 아뇨
- 그 배는 제 겁니다
- 뭐?
What?
뭐라고?
네 얘기 듣고 보니까
나도 갖고 싶잖아
-The stuff you said, I want that!
-But you don't have $20,000!
너한텐 2만 달러가 없어
어떻게든 마련하면 되잖아
미스터 보먼트는 내 거야
Who cares? I'll make payments!
I want the Mr. Bowmont!
너희들 돌아왔구나
-Oh, my God. You're back.
-Let me see it. Let me see your hand.
어디 손 좀 보자
Why do you wanna see my hand?
내 손은 왜?
뭐 들고 있나 보게
무슨 쓰레기야?
I wanna see what's in your hand.
I wanna see the trash.
정말 더럽네
얼른 갖다버려라
It's all dirty.
You should throw this out.
알았어
-What did you just do?
-What happened?
- 이게 무슨 짓이야?
- 어떻게 된 거니?
-Richard was there. I couldn't do it.
-Oh, no.
리처드가 나타나서
산통 다 깨졌어
아니 되오
내일 터뜨릴 거야
I was gonna surprise her tomorrow.
놀래주려고 했는데
너희들이 망쳐놨어
-Now you've ruined it.
-We didn't.
우리가 망치다니
들어서자마자 손 보자는
사람이 어디 있냐
Who walks in a room
and asks to see a person's hands?
손금 보는 사람
손톱 손질하는 사람
A palm reader, a manicurist,
a hand doctor...
손 전문의
-Glove salesman.
-Good one!
- 장갑 장사
- 그거 좋다
This is terrible. What will I do?
엉망이 됐어
어떡하면 좋지?
모니카는 의심만 했지
확실한 건 모르니까
She only suspects something.
So just throw her off the track.
딴청을 부리는 거야
I'll pretend marriage
is the last thing on my mind.
맞아, 결혼 따위엔 전혀
관심 없는 척해야겠다
그래, 결혼해서 한 여자에게
구속당하기 싫은 것처럼
Convince her you're scared
of commitment, that you're a coward.
I can do that.
I've had years of practice.
그건 쉽지, 30년 동안
연습한 거니까
Being you is finally gonna pay off!
네 인간됨이 드디어
빛을 보는구나
피자박스가 박혀있어서
밑에까지 내려갔다 왔어
Some idiot keeps stuffing
the trash chute with pizza boxes.
That guy is still doing that?
그 자식이 아직도
그 버릇 못 고쳤네?
얘들아, 어머나
너 왔구나, 손 좀 봐
Oh, my God. Let me see your hand!
You're too late!
She already took out the trash!
너무 늦었어, 쓰레기는
벌써 갖다버렸다구
안녕
어서 오세요
Look, Elizabeth, we have to talk.
엘리자베스
할 얘기가 있어
이렇게 깔끔하게
끝내보긴 처음이야
I have never had
such a healthy breakup.
She was such a grownup about it.
정말 어른스러운 애라니까
She didn't seem too immature for me.
결코 철이 없는 게 아냐
Did I just make a huge mistake?
혹시 큰 실수를 한 건 아닐까?
Ross! Wait!
교수님, 잠깐만요!
Elizabeth, thank God.
I was just thinking about..
엘리자베스, 다행이다
나도 방금 같은 생각을...
이 쪼다야!
You suck!
What?
뭐?
좋아
여전히 깨진 상태야
Breakup's still on.
Here she comes. Do I look like
I don't wanna get married?
저기 모니카 온다, 나 어때?
결혼하기 싫은 사람 같냐?
그래
그리고 어딘지 모르게
프랑스 녀석 같기도 하다
And, also, a little like a French guy.
전엔 몰랐었는데
I never noticed that before.
얘들아
- 어서 와
- 그래
뭐하고 있어?
-What are you up to?
-Hanging out. Talking about websites.
어떤 웹사이트
얘기 좀 하느라고
아무렴
결혼을 주제로 한
사이트가 있는데
We saw this interesting website
about marriage...
결혼은 아무짝에도 쓸모 없고
and how unnecessary it is, a way
for the government to keep tabs.
정부가 개인을 통제하기 위한
제도에 불과하다는군
그래, '빅 브라더'처럼
Yeah, Big Brother.
그건 조금 심한데?
That's a bit crazy.
자기 인터넷 활용 분야가
넓어진 건 반가운 일이지만
Although I am glad you're looking
at other things on the lnternet.
생각해보니 그럴 듯해
대체 왜 결혼들을 하지?
Got me thinking.
Why would anybody want to get married?
왜라니
To celebrate the relationship,
solidify the commitment...
둘의 관계에 공고한 의미를
부여하고 기념하기 위해서지
서로에 대한 사랑을
세상에 공표하면서
declare your love for one another
to the world.
그렇군
자기 생각이 그렇다면야
Well, that's good to know.
미스터 보먼트가 왔다!
The Mr. Bowmont is here!
A diner wants to compliment you.
Shall I let him in?
모니카, 주방장께 찬사를
전하겠다는 손님이 있는데
- 들여보내도 될까요?
- 그럼, 이 맛에 요리하는데
Sure. I love this part.
-Come on in.
-Hi.
들어오세요
안녕
-Richard.
-I'm not here to compliment the chef.
리처드
사실 칭찬하러 온 건 아냐
I hate when people come back
to compliment the chef.
괜찮아요
그런 칭찬은 싫어하니까
내가 요리밖에 못하나?
Like I have nothing better to do.
무슨 일이죠?
So, what's up?
It was great seeing you
the other night.
지난번 식당에서 만나서
정말 반가웠어
나도 반가웠어요
Good to see you too.
-You came to tell me that?
-I came to tell you something else.
그 말하려고 온 거예요?
아니, 다른 얘길 하고 싶어서
I came here to tell you
I still love you.
아직 당신을 사랑한다는
말을 하려고 왔어
네? 뭐? 뭐라구요?
What? What did you..? What?
아직 당신을 사랑해
I still love you.
이런 말하면 안 되는 거겠지
난 챈들러 그 친구도 좋아해
I know I shouldn't even
be here telling you this.
You're with Chandler, who I like.
게이가 아니래도 믿을 거야
If you say he's straight,
I'll believe you.
After seeing you, I knew if I didn't
tell you I'd regret it.
그날 밤 당신을 본 후 이 말을
안 하면 평생 후회할 것 같았어
당신과 헤어진 건
일생일대의 실수였어
Letting you go was
the stupidest thing I ever did.
You're really not
supposed to be back here.
주방에 들어오면 안 돼요
그래, 미안해
I'm sorry. I know this is
the wrong time and the wrong place...
시기도 장소도
어울리진 않지만
꼭 말해야겠어
but I had to tell you.
I wanna spend my life with you.
I wanna marry you.
함께 살고 싶어, 결혼해 줘
당신과 아이도 낳고 싶어
I wanna have kids with you.
세상에...
Oh, my God.
Why don't they put chairs back here?
여긴 왜 의자가 없지?
날벼락 같은 소리겠지만
너무 늦은 건가?
Look, I know this is crazy,
but am I too late?
You're too late.
Where was all this three years ago?
네, 너무 늦었어요
3년 전엔 뭘 했어요?
알아, 내가 바보였어
I know. I was an idiot.
I tried to forget you. I really did.
당신을 잊으려고 노력했지
정말이야, 작년에
같이 점심 먹고
After our last lunch, I spent
six months in Africa trying to forget.
6개월 동안 아프리카에서
당신을 잊어보려고 했어
-What did you do there?
-Work with blind kids.
- 거기서 뭐했어요?
- 눈먼 아이들을 돌봤어
What are you doing to me?
대체 왜 이러는 거예요
Look, I...
미안하지만...
이건 아니에요
I'm sorry,
but this is not gonna happen.
That's fine. I'll walk away.
I'll never bother you again.
알았어, 좋아
내가 포기하지
다신 괴롭히지 않을게
Only if you say Chandler's willing
to give you everything I am.
다만 챈들러의 마음도
나와 같다는 것만 확인하면
물론이에요
네, 그럼요
Well, he is. I mean...
marriage is all he talks about.
My goodness!
챈들러도 입만 열면
결혼 얘기예요
사실 지금 결혼을
미루는 건 나예요
In fact, I'm the one making him wait.
- 당신이?
- 네
You are? Why?
- 왜?
- 왜냐구요?
Why?
정부 때문이죠
Because of the government.
- 놀랍지 않아?
- 그래
Isn't it incredible?
모니카랑 챈들러가 결혼하다니
Monica and Chandler
are getting married.
그래, 정말 잘살 거야
I know. They'll be so happy together.
How often do two best friends
fall in love?
두 친구가 사랑에
빠지는 게 흔한 일이니?
- 절대 흔하지 않지
- 그럼
-Not that often.
-No.
둘이 잘돼서 너무 기뻐
-I'm so happy for them.
-Me too. So happy for them.
나도 너무 기뻐
I'm so happy and not at all jealous.
샘은 하나도 안 나
Oh, no! God, definitely not jealous.
당연하지
우리가 왜 샘을 내니
기쁜 마음이 98%라면
샘나는 건 2% 정도?
I'm probably 98% happy
and maybe 2% jealous.
- 2%는 별거 아니잖아
- 그럼
-I mean, what's 2%? That's nothing.
-Totally.
- 난 90대 10이야
- 그래, 나도
-I'm like 90/10.
-Yeah. Me too.
얘들아
챈들러 못 봤냐?
Have you guys seen Chandler?
아니, 근데 누가 너 찾더라
테닐 선장이라고
No. But you know
who was looking for you?
Tennille.
The marriage stuff you were saying
yesterday? You don't believe that.
어제 그 결혼 얘기
정말 그렇게 생각해?
당연하지
Sure, I do. In fact, I think the
concept of marriage is unnatural.
사실 결혼이란 개념 자체가
부자연스러워
돼지들을 봐
Look at pigs. Let's take
a second here and look at pigs.
여기서 잠시 돼지들의
삶을 들여다보자고
Pigs don't mate for life.
돼지는 배우자가 없어
평생 짝짓기 파트너가
수백 마리는 될 거야
A pig can have 100 sexual partners
in a lifetime.
소수의 근육질 돼지가 아니라
다수의 평범한 돼지들 말이야
That's an ordinary pig,
not even a pig that's good at sports.
Yeah, but that's pigs, not people.
하지만 그건 돼지잖아
사람이 아니라
결혼이 좋다면 내가 왜 반대해
이 나라의 이혼율을 알고 있어?
If marriage worked, I'd be for it.
Do you know the divorce rate?
97%야
Ninety-seven percent!
잠깐
Wait a minute.
그럼 절대 결혼은
안 하겠다는 뜻이니?
Are you telling me
you may never want to get married?
- 누구 말인데?
- 너! 너 말이야
-Who's to say?
-You! You are to say!
절대라고는 못하지만
아마 절대가 되겠지
Never say never, but, probably...
yeah, never.
세상에
Oh, my God. Then what are we
even doing? What is this?
그럼 우린 뭐하고 있지?
이건 대체 뭐야?
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
What is all this pressure?
왜 이렇게 사람을 밀어붙여
이건 또 새로운 작전인가?
Is this some new strategy?
대체 누구 발목을
잡으려는 술수야?
Why don't you put down your copy
of The Rules, huh, mantrap?
됐어, 나 갈래
You know what? I gotta go.
괜찮아요, 계획이 있으니까
It's okay. I got a plan.
- 우리도 짝을 만날 거야
- 물론이지
-We're gonna find love.
-Definitely.
Yeah, I'm pretty confident about that.
안 나타나고 배기겠어?
That's what makes it so easy to be
80% happy for Monica and Chandler.
그러니까 모니카랑 챈들러를
축복하는 맘이 80%나 되지
- 그래도 확실한 게 필요한데
- 무슨 소리야?
-A guarantee would be nice.
-What do you mean?
Some friends make a deal.
친구끼리 그런 약속하잖아
Like if neither of them are married
by 40, they marry each other.
'40살까지 미혼이면
우리 둘이 결혼하자'
-A backup?
-Exactly.
- 안심보험 말이구나
- 맞아, 그거야
그래, 난 들어놨어
Yeah, I've got that.
- 정말?
- 응
You do?
-Who?
-Joey.
누군데?
- 조이
- 조이?
-Joey? Are you serious?
-I locked him in years ago.
- 그래
- 진짜야?
몇 년 전부터 가둬놨어
Wait. So if neither of you are
married by 40, you'll marry Joey?
그럼 40살까지 미혼이면
조이랑 결혼하겠다는 거야?
Yep. We shook on it.
그래, 새끼손가락 걸었어
But believe me, that is not
how he wanted to seal the deal.
조이가 원한 계약 방식은
그런 게 아니었지만
Oh, seriously?
그래?
정확히 이러더라
I think his exact words were..
Charming.
못 말려
He's just a backup.
- 어차피 안심보험인데 뭘
- 하긴
-Hey, Monica.
-Have you seen Rachel? Or a mirror?
너 왔냐?
레이첼이나 거울 봤니?
-It's for my boat. Pretty cool, huh?
-Yeah, it's great.
요트에 맞춘 건데 괜찮지?
그래, 멋있다
무슨 일인데 그래?
이 선장님한테 털어놔 봐
What's wrong? Talk to the captain.
Just realizing
I'm in a dead-end relationship.
두 사람 관계가 막다른 골목에
다다랐다는 느낌 알아?
-Chandler being difficult?
-I don't want marriage tomorrow.
챈들러가 속 썩이는구나
누가 내일 당장 결혼하재?
하지만 아무 가망 없는 관계에
시간만 낭비하고 있을 순 없잖아
But I wanna know we're going
somewhere, that I'm not wasting time.
-You know Chandler.
-No, I don't know Chandler.
- 너도 그 녀석 잘 알잖아
- 아니, 모르겠어
Not anymore.
It's like something's changed.
요즘은 더 그래
뭔가 변한 것 같아
-Maybe you changed.
-I didn't change.
네가 변한 건지도 모르지
난 변한 거 없어
Maybe that's the problem.
아마 그게 문제일 거야
뭐?
-What?
-Chandler is a complex fellow.
챈들러는 복잡한 녀석이야
마누라를 볼 놈이 아니라고
One who is unlikely to take a wife.
Is that some kind of boat talk?
그건 뱃사람들 표현이니?
I haven't totally decided
how to talk on my boat yet.
글쎄, 아직 말투를
결정 못했어
그럼 나더러 무작정
기다리는 뜻이야?
Does he think
I'll wait around for nothing?
현실을 받아들여
Face it.
Chandler is against marriage.
챈들러는 결혼을 싫어해
앞으로도 그럴 거야
And always will be.
There's some people
who do wanna marry me.
좋아, 나랑 결혼하고
싶다는 사람도 있어
정말?
-There are?
-Yeah. Richard.
그래, 리처드
Richard said he wants to marry you?
리처드가 너랑 결혼하재?
챈들러는 결혼이
끔찍하다고 날뛰는데?
-And Chandler says he hates marriage?
-That's right.
맞아
챈들러 결혼 엄청 좋아해
Chandler loves marriage!
You just said he hates marriage!
방금 끔찍하게 싫어한댔잖아
"He's a complex fellow
who's unlikely to take a wife"!
너무 복잡해서 마누라를
볼 녀석도 아니고
앞으로도 결혼에는
찬성하지 않을 거라며
"He's against marriage
and always will be"!
내 말을 그렇게 이해했어?
You got that from what I said?
After the Cretaceous Period,
the dinosaurs were gone.
백악기 이후 공룡은
지상에서 멸종됩니다
What happened, you guys?
너희들 정말 어떻게 된 거니?
-Rach.
-Hey, you.
- 레이첼
- 나야
- 그래, 들어와
- 고마워
-Come on in.
-Thank you.
I'm so sorry
to hear about you and Elizabeth.
엘리자베스 일은 정말 유감이다
Thanks. I really thought
we'd be able to make it work.
고마워, 잘될 거라고
생각했는데
- 역시 인연이 아니었나봐
- 그래, 사랑이라...
I guess it wasn't meant to be.
Yeah. Love.
It's a tricky business, isn't it?
정말 뜻대로 안 되는 거지?
맞아
-I guess so.
-So, what do you say we make a pact?
그러니까 우리 약속하자
If you and I are both single by 40,
we get married.
둘 다 40살까지 싱글이면
나랑 결혼하는 걸로
I mean, we know each other,
we like each other...
서로에 대해 잘 알고
서로 좋아하잖아
we've already slept together,
so there'll be no surprises.
더구나 한 침대도 써봤으니
놀랄 일도 없고
무슨 뜻인지 알지?
'그게 대체 뭐야?'
No, like, "What's that?"
그러니까 안심보험을
들겠다는 거구나
-Oh, you want me to be your backup.
-Exactly.
맞아
Yeah. I already have one.
난 이미 약속한 사람 있어
-What? Who?
-Phoebe.
뭐? 누구랑?
- 피비
- 피비?
Phoebe?
걔는 조이랑 약속했다던데?
But she just said Joey is her backup.
그럴 리가 있나
Oh, I don't think so.
We just spoke. She said
that she and Joey made a deal.
방금 피비한테 들었는걸
조이랑 약속했다고 했어
말도 안 돼
우린 몇 년 전에 약속했어
That's impossible. We have had
a deal for years. We shook on it.
새끼손가락 걸고
Although, believe me,
she wanted to do a lot more than that.
물론 피비는
그 이상을 원했지만
건터, 조이예요
챈들러 거기 있어요?
Gunther, it's Joey. Is Chandler there?
Listen. What kind of muffins
do they serve at sea?
저기...
바다에선 어떤 머핀을 먹죠?
대체 어디 갔었어?
Where the hell have you been?!
교수님이랑 코코넛 전화기
만들고 있었다
I was making a coconut phone
with the Professor.
Richard told Monica
he wants to marry her.
리처드가 모니카한테
결혼하고 싶다고 했대
-What?
-I've been trying to find you.
뭐?
그래, 당장 널 찾아서
연기 그만두라고 해야되는데
이 빌어먹을 보트 신발이
자꾸 벗겨지는 거야
And I would have if these damn
boat shoes wouldn't keep flying off!
- 맙소사
- 그러게, 진짜 엿 같아!
-Oh, my God!
-I know! They suck!
He's not supposed to ask her
to marry him! I am!
자기가 뭔데 날 제쳐 두고
내 여자한테 청혼을 해?
- 누가 아니래
- 참 내...
-I know!
-What..?
You know what I'll do?
I'll go over there and kick his ass!
내가 당장 쫓아가서
아예 작살을 내주겠어
도와줄 거지?
Will you help me?
Look, I don't think us getting
our asses kicked is a solution, okay?
어차피 우리가 작살날 텐데
그런다고 해결이 되겠냐?
- 일단 모니카부터 찾아야지
- 맞아, 그래야겠다
-Look, just go and find Monica.
-You're right.
Okay. I'm gonna get the ring...
반지 어디 있지?
반지를 가져가서
모니카 보는 대로
I'm gonna go find her
and I'm gonna propose!
청혼해버릴 거야
- 그래
- 좋았어
야, 잠깐만
Dude! Dude! Dude!
코코넛 전화 다 만들면
내 요트에 갖다 놓자
That coconut phone
might be good for the boat.
Hi.
나예요
그래
I don't know why I'm here.
여기 왜 왔는지 모르겠어요
누가 물어봤나?
I didn't ask.
들어올 거야?
-You wanna come in?
-I don't know.
모르겠어요
좋아
Oh, okay.
I'll just leave the door open
and sit on the couch.
이대로 문 열어놓고
소파에 앉아 있을게
-Chandler is such an idiot!
-Drink?
- 챈들러는 멍청이예요
- 술 줘?
-Scotch on the..
-Rocks with a twist?
네
- 스카치에...
- 얼음하고 레몬?
I remember.
기억하고 있지
You still smoking cigars?
요즘도 시가 피워요?
아니, 그건 예술이야
No, no. That's art.
If it bothers you,
I can put my art out.
신경 쓰이면 예술 끄지 뭐
No, that's okay.
아뇨, 괜찮아요
So, Monica, let me ask you a question.
모니카
하나 물어볼까?
Since we broke up, do you ever...
우리가 헤어지고 난 뒤...
think about me?
내 생각한 적 있나?
네, 사실 몇 달 전에도
생각이 나더라구요
Actually, I thought about you
a few months ago.
정말?
-Really?
-But it's because...
눈에 이상이 생겼는데
의사가 맘에 안 들어서
I had an eye exam,
and I don't like my new eye doctor.
-Who is it?
-Edward Nevsky.
- 누구였는데?
- 에드워드 네브스키
He's no good.
맞아, 그 친구 별로지
Do you ever think about me...
달리 생각은 안 해봤어?
안과의사 말고
-in a non-eye-doctor way?
-No.
네
Because getting over you was
the hardest thing I've ever done.
당신을 잊는 게 너무 힘들어서
I never let myself think about you.
일부러 생각을 안 한 거예요
Wow.
Phoebe, you picked Joey and Ross?
피비
로스하고도 약속했다며
안심보험을 두 개나 들어?
-You can't have two backups!
-Of course I can.
안 될 거 없잖아
It's good sense
to back up your backup.
안심보험의 안심보험을
들어두면 더 좋은 거지
- 벌써 챈들러도 놓쳤잖아
- 뭐?
-Look, I've already lost Chandler.
-What?
야, 피비
Hey, Phoebe! We're both your backup?
우리가 다 네 안심보험이냐?
How could you do this to me?
피비, 너 나한테 이럴 수 있어?
Why are you complaining?
You were both aware of the situation.
왜들 이러는지 모르겠다
둘 다 알고 있었잖아
-I was not!
-No, we weren't!
- 천만에
- 알긴 누가 알아
This kind of backtalk won't fly
when we're married.
결혼 후엔 이런 식의
말대꾸는 용서 못해
둘 다 가질 순 없어
You can't have both. Pick one.
- 하나만 골라
- 날 골라
-Pick me!
-No, pick me!
안 돼, 날 골라
몽달귀신 되긴 싫어
-I don't wanna end up an old maid.
-All right. Well, let's see.
좋아, 어디 보자
로스는 자상한 아빠고...
Ross is a good father.
But...
조이는 요트가 있지
결정하기 힘들다
Joey has a boat. This is hard.
This is crazy.
I wanna switch to Rachel.
기가 막혀서
난 레이첼로 바꿀래
나도 레이첼로 바꾼다
-I wanna switch to Rachel too.
-No, wait. Just wait.
안 돼, 잠깐 기다려
성급하게 결정할 일이 아냐
Wait, guys.
Don't make any rash decisions.
내가 한 약속 기억하지?
Just remember my promise:
If we get married, three times a week.
나랑 결혼하면
일주일에 세 번이야
Oh, my God. Phoebe...
맙소사, 피비...
- 마사지 얘기야
- 그렇구나
I'm talking about massages.
No, I'm not.
이렇게 해결하자
나한테 좋은 수가 있어
I know how to settle it.
We'll do this.
냅킨 한 장에 조이라고 적고
다른 냅킨엔 로스라고 써서
I'm gonna write "Joey"
on one napkin...
and "Ross" on the other napkin
and we're gonna pick one.
너랑 나랑 제비를 뽑아
짝을 결정하는 거야
That person will be our backup. Okay?
- 됐지? 어서 뽑아
- 그거 괜찮다, 좋아
-Sounds fair.
-All right.
Good. Switching them up.
자, 그럼 섞는다
- 골라
- 왼쪽
-Pick one.
-Left.
- 고맙다
- 별말씀을
-Thank you.
-You're welcome.
-Ross.
-Joey.
- 로스
- 조이
-We should switch.
-Absolutely.
- 우리 바꾸자
- 그거 좋지
보고 싶었다
납작이 흉물단지야
I missed you,
you ugly flat-faced old freak.
뭐라고?
Excuse me?
얘 말이에요
Him.
이 아파트도 그리웠어요
I missed this apartment.
Now, this is a grownup's apartment.
이런 게 어른의 아파트죠
내겐 어른이 필요해요
무슨 뜻인지 알죠?
I should be with a grownup, you know?
물론, 그러니까...
You're saying you need to be
with someone more mature.
보다 성숙한 사람과
지내고 싶다는 거지
예를 들면...
Maybe someone with...
의사면허가 있다거나
a license to practice medicine.
콧수염이 있다거나
Or a mustache.
솔직히 말하죠
Let's face it. I'm not a kid anymore.
난 어린애가 아니에요
내 마음을 잘 헤아려주는
남자가 필요해요
I need someone
who wants the same things.
직장으로 찾아와 사랑한다고
고백하는 남자, 바로 그런 거
Coming to my work and telling me
you love me, I want that!
점심 먹으면서 돼지 짝짓는
얘기하는 남자, 그거 싫어요
Talking about pig sex over lunch,
I don't want that!
I think that's fair.
그거 말 되는군
Please, don't even talk
to me about fair.
말이 돼요? 내 앞에서
그런 소리 말아요
Fair would've been you
wanting to marry me then.
그때 나한테 청혼했다면
말이 됐겠죠
지금 챈들러가 청혼하면
말이 되는 거고
Or Chandler wanting to marry me now.
이건 전혀 말이
안 되는 상황이에요
Believe me, nothing
about this is fair. Nothing.
전혀, 전혀, 전혀, 전혀...
-Nothing! Nothing!
-It's okay.
됐어, 그만 진정해
Nothing.
전혀
I don't know.
정말 혼란스러워요
모르겠어요
I don't know.
그렇겠지
I know.
아무래도 정리를 좀 해야겠어요
I have to figure some..
Some stuff, before I can...
- 결정하기 전에
- 그래, 이해해
I understand.
천천히 생각하라고
Take as much time as you want.
Ten, even 20 minutes, if you need it.
필요하다면 20분도 좋아
기다리고 있을게
I'll be here. Not smoking.
담배 안 피우고
챈들러
모니카 어디 있죠?
Where is she?
당신 하나도 안 무서워요
I'm not scared of you.
모니카는 여기 없어
들어와도 좋네
She's not here. And please come in.
얼음 넣은 스카치
Scotch on the rocks...
레몬즙, 받침접시까지?
with a twist, on a coaster.
모니카 나와라
Monica?
좋아, 왔었는데
아까 돌아갔어
Okay, she was here. But she left.
Where did she go?
어디로 갔죠?
생각할 게 좀 있다더군
She said she had to think things over.
Oh, my God. I can't believe this.
I thought you were a good guy.
정말 기가 막히네요
난 당신이...
좋은 분인 줄 알았어요
- 이봐, 아무 일도 없었어
- 정말 아무 일도 없었나요?
Look, nothing happened.
Nothing? So you didn't tell
my girlfriend you love her?
내 여자한테 사랑을
고백해 놓고?
좋아, 그 일은 있었군
Well, all right, one thing happened.
이게 대체 무슨 짓이죠?
내 여자가 생각에 빠져있어요
You know what you did?
My girlfriend is thinking things over.
왜 생각하게 만드냐구요!
You made my girlfriend think!
그렇담 미안하네
Well, I'm sorry.
-What's to think about? I love her.
-Well...
생각할 게 뭐가 있죠?
난 모니카를 사랑해요
글쎄... 자네가 못 준 걸
내가 주려는 거야
I'm willing to offer her
things that you aren't.
those things. I had a plan...
저도 기꺼이 줄 생각입니다
절차라는 게 있잖아요
to throw her off so when I offered
all these things, she'd be surprised.
관심 없는 척하다 청혼해서
놀래주고 싶었던 거라구요
잘됐군, 효과만점이었어
If it helps, it worked very well.
잘난 아저씨 나타나기 전에는
아무 문제없었어요
It was working till you showed up,
you big tree.
이건 불공평해요
This isn't fair.
당신한테도 기회가 있었지만
그 기회를 날려버렸잖아요
You had your chance with her,
and you blew it!
This is my chance. I won't blow it,
because we are meant for each other.
내게 다가온 기회는 놓칠 수
없어요, 우린 서로 사랑하니까
정말 기가 막힐 노릇이군요
And this has all just been
one stupid mistake!
오늘 청혼할 작정이었어요
I was gonna propose tonight.
- 청혼하겠다고?
- 네, 그래요
-You were gonna propose?
-Yeah, I even...
반지도 샀습니다
반지 있어요?
got a ring. Did you get a ring?
아니, 준비 못했네
No, I don't have a ring.
가서 모니카를 잡게
You go get her, Chandler.
충고 한 마디 할까?
And can I give you a piece of advice?
일단 잡으면...
If you do get her...
절대 놓치지 말게
후회하기 싫다면
don't let her go.
Trust me.
리처드
You know, Richard, you are a good guy.
당신은 좋은 분이에요
알아
I know.
그게 내 비극이지
I hate that.
- 야
- 나 지금 모니카 찾아야 돼
-I've gotta find Monica.
-She's gone.
떠났어
뭐?
-What?
-She had a bag and she left.
가방 싸 들고 가버렸다니까
무슨 소리야?
-What?
-She was all crying...
너랑 맘이 안 맞는다면서
얼마나 눈물을 흘리던지
She said you guys
want different things.
생각할 시간이 필요하대
붙들고 다 연극이었다고 말하지
-Why didn't you tell her it was a plan?
-I told her everything.
그랬어, 다 얘기했는데
안 믿는 걸 어떡해
-But she wouldn't believe me.
-Well, where..? Where did she go?
그럼...
어디로 간대?
부모님한테 간 거 같아
전화는 하지 말라더라
To her parents'. She said you shouldn't
call. But if I were you, I would.
하지만 나라면 전화할 거야
-I can't believe I ruined this.
-I am so sorry, man.
정말 미치겠다
어떡하면 좋냐
날 놀래주고 싶었다면서
You wanted it to be a surprise.
세상에...
Oh, my God.
Chandler...
챈들러?
내 인생에...
in all my life...
이런 행운이 찾아오리라곤
상상도 못했어
I never thought
I would be so lucky...
너와 사랑에 빠지게 되다니
as to fall in love with my best...
내 가장 친한...
My best...
- 이래서 남자들이 하는 거야
- 알았어, 그래
There's a reason why
girls don't do this!
내가 할게
I'll do it. I thought...
난...
Wait, I can do this.
잠깐, 할 수 있어
난 이 말을 어디서 어떻게
해야 하나 그것만 고민했어
I thought that it mattered...
what I said or where I said it.
그런데 이제 깨달았어
Then I realized...
the only thing that matters
is that you...
중요한 건 너 뿐이란 사실을
네가 내게 가져다준 행복
예전엔 존재하는지조차 몰랐어
You make me happier
than I ever thought I could be.
너만 허락한다면
And if you let me...
I'll spend all my life trying
to make you feel the same way.
평생을 함께 하며 네게도
그런 행복을 주고 싶어
모니카
Monica...
나와 결혼해줄래?
will you marry me?
좋아
Yes.
넌 분명히 마누라를
볼 남자였어
I knew you were likely to take a wife!
좀 들어가자
궁금해 미치겠다
Can we come in yet?
We're dying out here!
다들 어서 들어와!
Come in! Come in!
우리 약혼했어!
We're engaged!
이렇게 샘이 안 날 수도 있니?
This is the least jealous
I've ever been.
Oh, no, wait! This is wrong!
Ross isn't here!
잠깐, 뭔가 이상해
로스가 여기 없잖아
Hell, he's done it three times.
He knows what it's about!
걔는 세 번이나 해봤잖아
이 기분 잘 알 거야